JAVIER RAMIREZ

Software Engineer

0033770407936

javier.ramirez.leiva0@gmail.com







Software engineer, lover of its work and willing to make a difference. I have an international experience in countries such as France and Spain as well as in different domains such as CAD, automotive industry, security and IoT. Currently working for Dassault Systemes in Lyon, France.

WORK EXPERIENCES

Software Engineer Dassault Systemes | 08/2019-Present

Electrical System Design app inside the CATIA portfolio of the 3DExperience platform from Dassault Systemes.

- C++ development for CAD and PLM applications to design electrical systems on Windows and Linux OS
- CI/CD management. Tools development on python and bash to improve process
- Development of UI elements based on web technologies
- Draft of technical software specifications and unit testing planning
- Software architecture design focused on re-usability and modules/frameworks
- Model definition for MBSE engineering

Software Engineer Continental | 01/2017-08/2019

AKKA Technologies on behalf of Continental Automotive France SAS. ECU software development to control a Direct Injection Engine inside the new E-Power technology for Nissan.

- Design of the system architecture for a real-time application. Focus on software reliability
- Software development on C/C++ code conforming the AUTOSAR standard
- Scripting (python and perl) to create automatic tests for validation and non-regression
- Team management, AKKA for Continental. Technical orientation and support of other employees
- Creation of software tools to help with task tracking and planning

Software Engineering Intern

Rockwell Collins | 03/2016-09/2016

Security application to control cameras using the detections made by the radar FMWC PSR-500

- C++ development using the QT framework for Windows and Linux OS
- Planning and specification of validation tests
- Software mock-ups for customer demos

Software Engineering Intern

Digi International | 02/2014-07/2014

Final Degree Project "Connection of any device to the Cloud Service "Etherios" at Digi International.

- Study of cloud services, "Internet of Things", Big Data and M2M communications
- Software development in C. Focus on communication socket development

EDUCATION

Master of Engineering. Electrical and Electronic engineering

ENSEEIHT (Ecole Nationale Supérieure d'Electrotechnique, d'Electronique, d'Informatique, d'Hydraulique et des Télécommunications) 2015 - 2016

Master of Engineering. Electrical and Electronic engineering

UPNA (Universidad Publica de Navarra) 2014 - 2015

Engineering degree. Electronic engineering

Universidad de La Rioja 2010 - 2014

LANGUAGES

Spanish(Native)

• English(Full professional proficienty)

French(Full professional proficienty)

SKILLS

Programming Languages

C, C++ (C++ 11)

Python (3.0), Bash, Perl

HTML, Javascript, CSS

Visual Basic, Matlab Script

Software Applications

Visual Studio, QT IDE, Eclipse

CATIA, 3D Experience

Git, SVN, JIRA

Matlab, Simulink, INCA, Canalyzer

Technologies

CAD, CAM,

Real-Time, Multicore

TCP-IP, SOAP, SSL/TLS

ECU, CAN bus, UART

Development Methods

V Cycle, Agile

Object Oriented Programming, design Patterns

Continuous integration, source control management